Shailesh Kumar

Software Engineer

7618629116



vipshaileshyadav94@gmail.com



Noida,India



SUMMARY

Technology-driven Software Engineer with 2 years of experience in functional specification into code modules and software solutions. Deep understanding of system integration testing and user acceptance testing. Engages in the software development lifecycle to support the development, configuration and modification. Drives the adoption of new technologies by researching innovative technology trends and developments.

EDUCATION

GLA University Mathura

Bachelor's Degree in Technology Computer Science and Engineering (8.1 CGPA) 2019 – 2023

INTERMEDIATE

2018 - 2019

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Programming Languages: JAVA
- Database Management: MySQL
- Web Technologies: HTML, CSS, Sass, JavaScript
- Libraries: React.JS, PIXI.JS, Three.JS
- Data Structures Algorithms, Object Oriented Programming
- Operating System: Windows 10

CERTIFICATIONS

- Certificate of Full Stack Developer from Udemy
- Completed certification course of Udemyon AWS Certified Core Knowledge
- Completed certification course of Networking Management Technologies

ACHIEVEMENTS

- Secured 438 rank among 6000
 participants in Credit Suisse Global Coding Challenge Competition 2021
- Shortlisted for the semi-final round of the Coding Contest at Code Gladiators 2021
- 5 Star on Hacker Rank.
- 250+ Problem Solved on Leet Code.
- Rank 123 out of 25k participants in Leet Code Weekly Contest 387.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer

Ingenuity Gaming Pvt. Ltd | 07/2022 - Present

- Designed and developed complete supporting features from back testing strategies.
- Utilized JavaScript to program logic,rules and Pixi.js in various game titles
- Continuously improving JavaScript programming skills and staying updated with the latest developments technologies.
- Writing unit tests and performing testing to ensure the reliability of the code. Conducting code reviews to maintain code quality.
- Participated in code reviews to ensure code quality and adherence to coding standards
- Technology Used: JavaScript, JAVA, PIXI.JS, Phaser, HTML and CSS.

Software Engineer Intern

Netcamp pvt.L | 06/2021-09/2021

- Under the team's direction, made a web page for the company's official website.
- Built front-end libraries and reusable components for efficient code maintenance and project consistency.
- Website accessibility and speed improvements have been made to guarantee a consistent user experience across all devices.
- I worked with the team to compile requirements, run tests, and make the necessary alterations for the best website usability.
- In fixing front-end difficulties and debugging code, shown great problem-solving abilities and attention to detail.
- participated actively in team meetings, bringing ideas and recommendations to improve the user design and experience.